Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Photographs 5141 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Photographs
1930-1960
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen (BLF&E)
5141 P
0.97 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Photographs.
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Photographs including image scans, ritual materials, photographs from award ceremonies and other miscellaneous photos
7938923
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 09, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers and Trainmen is a labor union originally founded in Marshall, Michigan in May 1863, and was called Brotherhood of the Footboard at the time. At the time it was the only trade organization for railroad workers. A year later they changed their name to Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers. They took their present name starting in 2004.
In the nineteenth century the Brotherhood generally took a conciliatory approach in dealing with railroad management, preferring to negotiate reasonable demands than to go on strike. The brotherhood was seen as elitist by other railway unions, and sometimes came into conflict during strikes.
In 1969 the B of LF&E merged with three other railway labor organizations to form the United Transportation Union.
In 2004 the Brotherhood merged with the teamsters.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5141: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records 5141 G: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Graphics 5141 MB: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Memorabilia 5147: Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers Records 5467: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Local 807 (Auburn, NY) Records 5475: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen General Chairman, Boston and Maine Railroad Records 5611: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Honorary Register of Disabled 5646: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Additional Records 5869: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Local 807 (Auburn, NY) Additional Records 6146 P: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen Photographs 6176: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Additional Records
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen -- Photographs; Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers (U.S.)
7938923
- Chairman George Irvine, 1915-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1 Photograph(s)
- Easterday image scans, ritual materials (Box 1, Folder 1CD)
  Photograph(s); 01.tif, 02.tif, 03.tif, 04.tif, 05.tif
- Denver Grand Delegation- Funeral of Pap Leach, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  1 Photograph(s); June 29, 1919
- Easterday image scans, ritual materials (Box 1, Folder 2CD)
  Photograph(s); 06.tif, 07.tif, 08.tif, 09.tif, 10.tif
- Grand Chief Engineers, 1863-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  1 Photograph(s) - 1 Contact sheet
- Easterday image scans, ritual materials (Box 1, Folder 3CD)
  Photograph(s); 11.tif, 12.tif, 13.tif, 14.tif
- Train No. 6 at Levitland, NY, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photos used in E-L Full Crew Law Hearing - January 12, 1965 (F.B. Boardman) (Box 267, Folder 1)
  information gathered from a note inside box -- 50 photographs
- Joint Protective Board of the B of LF (Box 268, Folder 1)
  Delaware and Hudson (D&H) system
- Joint Protective Board of the B of LF and B of LE (Box 268, Folder 2)
- B of LF&E Officers, 1916 (Box 268, Folder 3)
  Several officers of the BLFE who were instrumental in pushing enactment of the Railroad Labor Act. Denver, Colorado
- Crooked River Canyon Bridge (Box 268, Folder 4)
  Central Oregon
- Presentation of the BLFE's D. B. Robertson Awards, 1958 (Box 268, Folder 5)
- Presentation of the BLFE's D. B. Robertson Awards, 1958 (Box 268, Folder 6)
- Unidentified (Box 268, Folder 7)
  Group of men
- NYS Legislative Board. BRT. First State Union Meeting, Albany, NY, Oct. 8-9, 1930; NYS Legislative Board. BRT. Sept. 24-28, 1946 (Box 269)
  - NYS Legislative Board. BRT. First State Union Meeting, Albany, NY, Oct. 8-9, 1930; NYS Legislative Board. BRT. Sept. 24-28, 1946, 1930-1946 (Box 269, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 270)